# **Alexander Anguiano**

#### **Profile**

Explorative and inquisitive data analyst uses critical thought processes to achieve desired results. Experienced teammate and leader in demanding and stressful work environments. Delivering analytics and visualizations, through data wrangling and feature engineering, with modern processing software.

# Recent Employment

# J.P. Morgan Chase - Business Process Analyst (2019 - Present)

- Reporting analyst for JP Morgan Chase Global Document Services (GDS).
- · Construct operational metrics from combination of multiple data reports and format sources.
- Initiated and established Tableau Server Project for GDS through JPMC Tableau Center of Excellence.
- Intelligent Solutions Controls owner and developer for GDS Tableau.
- · Authoring of SOP's, initiating of change alerts, and updating of reports inventory tracker for assigned projects.
- · Actively working to modernize reporting through, and train other associates on, Tableau and Alteryx.

### Norwex USA - Operations Leader (2015 - 2017)

- · Data reporting for KPI, employee metrics, and inventory tracking.
- Leader of up to 30 associates in E-commerce fulfillment operations.
- · Launched new Support Department for special orders, returns, and damages.

### FedEx Ground - Dock Manager (2014 - 2015)

- · Quality Driven Management analytics and improvement champion for facility.
- Managed more than 20 associates in high volume, high velocity, sort operation.
- · Oversaw accurate processing of parcels for dispatch within a prescribed time frame.
- Safety leader for shift operations staffed with 100+ employees.

# Personal Projects

# Microsoft Professional Capstone: Data Science

Developed a machine learning solution for Microsoft final project using R programming. Model included reading in of .csv, imputation of missing data, 10-fold cross validation, 7 regression algorithms, RMSE & R2 plots, predictions with .csv write output, variable importance scores, and correlation matrix. Project also required an Executive Summary report which contained description of variables, data exploration overview with histogram, data preparation techniques, model summary with RMSE plots, as well as variable importance and correlation visualizations.

#### **Sports Analytics Prediction Models**

Ensemble of 8 regression algorithms, including linear, SVM, boosted tree, and Keras multi-layered neural net, for NASCAR and NFL machine learning predictions model. Scoring predictions from the ensemble are used in a R programming lineup optimizer which will generate the best teams from pool of players.

#### **Education**

# University of Texas at Arlington – Bachelor of Arts English

- · Critical thinking for application of interpretation theory to multi-cultural, world, and U.S. literature.
- Technical writing and text editing skills, essential for document creation and written communication.

#### **Military**

#### **United States Navy - Veteran**

After 8-week bootcamp at Recruit Training Command in Great Lakes IL., went through 8 months of rigorous advanced aviation electronics A-school in Millington, TN. Assigned to the aircraft carrier USS George Washington CVN-73 and served in the ships Aviation Intermediate Maintenance Department troubleshooting and providing component level repair to aviation electronic countermeasure systems. Secondary duty assignment was to shipboard damage control and firefighting team. Completed 4-year commitment and separated with an Honorable Discharge (DD214 available upon request).

# Certifications & Courses

- · Tableau Certified Desktop Specialist
- JP Morgan Chase Tableau Academy
- · Microsoft Professional Program Capstone: Data Science
- Microsoft Analyzing and Visualizing Data with Power BI
- · Microsoft Querying Data with Transact-SQL
- · Microsoft Data Science Essentials